db.question.insert({"question":"Radiocarbon is produced in the atmosphere as a result of","choices":["collision between fast neutrons and nitrogen nuclei present in the atmosphere","action of ultraviolet light from the sun on atmospheric oxygen","action of solar radiations particularly cosmic rays on carbon dioxide present in the atmosphere","lightning discharge in atmosphere"],"answer":1,"level":2})
db.question.insert({"question":"The absorption of ink by blotting paper involves","choices":["viscosity of ink","capillary action phenomenon ","diffusion of ink through the blotting","siphon action"],"answer":2,"level":2})
db.question.insert({"question":"Siphon will fail to work if","choices":["the densities of the liquid in the two vessels are equal","the level of the liquid in the two vessels are at the same height","both its limbs are of unequal length","the temperature of the liquids in the two vessels are the same"],"answer":2,"level":3})
db.question.insert({"question":"Nuclear sizes are expressed in a unit named","choices":["Fermi","angstrom","newton","tesla"],"answer":1,"level":3})
db.question.insert({"question":"Light from the Sun reaches us in nearly","choices":["2 minutes","4 minutes","8 minutes","16 minutes"],"answer":3,"level":1})
db.question.insert({"question":"Stars appears to move from east to west because","choices":["all stars move from east to west","the earth rotates from west to east","the earth rotates from east to west","the background of the stars moves from west to east"],"answer":2,"level":3})
db.question.insert({"question":"Pa(Pascal) is the unit for","choices":["thrust","pressure","frequency","onductivity"],"answer":2,"level":1})
db.question.insert({"question":"Let a thin capillary tube be replaced with another tube of insufficient length then, we find water","choices":["will overflow","will not rise","depressed","hange its meniscus"],"answer":2,"level":2})
db.question.insert({"question":"Rectifiers are used to convert","choices":["Direct current to Alternating current","Alternating current to Direct current","high voltage to low voltage","low voltage to high voltage"],"answer":2,"level":3})
db.question.insert({"question":"On a rainy day, small oil films on water show brilliant colours. This is due to","choices":["dispersion","interference","diffraction","polarization"],"answer":2,"level":1})
db.question.insert({"question":"The nucleus of an atom consists of","choices":["electrons and neutrons","electrons and protons","protons and neutrons","All of the above"],"answer":"3","level":1})
db.question.insert({"question":"The number of moles of solute present in 1 kg of a solvent is called its","choices":["molality","molarity","normality","formality"],"answer":"1","level":2})
db.question.insert({"question":"The most electronegative element among the following is","choices":["sodium","bromine","fluorine","oxygen"],"answer":"3","level":3})
db.question.insert({"question":"The metallurgical process in which a metal is obtained in a fused state is called ","choices":["smelting","roasting","calcinations","froth floatation"],"answer":"1","level":1})
db.question.insert({"question":"The molecules of which gas have highest speed? ","choices":["H2 at -73oC","CH4 at 300 K","N2 at 1,027oC","O2 at 0oC"],"answer":"1","level":2})
db.question.insert({"question":"The law which states that the amount of gas dissolved in a liquid is proportional to its partial pressure is ","choices":["Dalton's law","Gay Lussac's law","Henry's law","Raoult's law"],"answer":"3","level":3})
db.question.insert({"question":"The gas present in the stratosphere which filters out some of the sun's ultraviolet light and provides an effective shield against radiation damage to living things is ","choices":["helium","ozone","oxygen","methane"],"answer":"2","level":1})
db.question.insert({"question":"The most commonly used bleaching agent is ","choices":["alcohol","carbon dioxide","chlorine","sodium chlorine"],"answer":"3","level":2})
db.question.insert({"question":"The nucleus of a hydrogen atom consists of ","choices":["1 proton only","1 proton + 2 neutron","1 neutron only","1 electron only"],"answer":"1","level":3})
db.question.insert({"question":"The metal that is used as a catalyst in the hydrogenation of oils is ","choices":["Ni","Pb","Cu","Pt"],"answer":"1","level":1})
db.question.insert({"question":"If in a frequently distribution, the mean and median are 21 and 22 respectively, then its mode is approximately","choices":["22.0","20.5","25.5","24.0"],"answer":"4","level":2})
db.question.insert({"question":"The area of the region bounded by the curves y = |x – 2|, x = 1, x = 3 and the x-axis is","choices":["1","2","3","4"],"answer":"1","level":3})
db.question.insert({"question":"Let A (2, –3) and B(–2, 1) be vertices of a triangle ABC. If the centroid of this triangle moves on the line 2x + 3y = 1, then the locus of the vertex C is the line","choices":["2x + 3y = 9","2x – 3y = 7","3x + 2y = 5","3x – 2y = 3"],"answer":"1","level":1})
db.question.insert({"question":"Distance between two parallel planes 2x + y + 2z = 8 and 4x + 2y + 4z + 5 = 0 is ","choices":["3/2","5/2","7/2","9/2"],"answer":"3","level":2})
db.question.insert({"question":" If the straight lines x = 1 + s, y = –3 – Ks, z = 1 + ls and x = , y = 1 + t, z = 2 – t with parameters s and t respectively, are co-planar then K equals ","choices":["-2","-1","-1/2","0"],"answer":"1","level":3})
db.question.insert({"question":"The mean and the variance of a binomial distribution are 4 and 2 respectively. Then the probability of 2 successes is ","choices":["37/256","219/256","128/256","28/256"],"answer":"4","level":1})
db.question.insert({"question":"The equation of the straight line passing through the point (4, 3) and making intercepts on the co-ordinate axes whose sum is –1 is ","choices":["x/2 + y/3 = -1 and x/-2 + y/1 = -1","x/2 - y/3 = -1 and x/-2 + y/1 = -1","x/2 + y/3 = 1 and x/2 + y/1 = 1","x/2 - y/3 = 1 and x/-2 + y/1 = 1"],"answer":"4","level":2})
db.question.insert({"question":"Suppose a population A has 100 observations 101, 102, … , 200, and another population B has 100 observations 151, 152, … , 250. If VA and VB represent the variances of the two populations, respectively, then VA/VB is ","choices":["1","9/4","4/9","2/3"],"answer":"1","level":3})
db.question.insert({"question":"The number of values of x in the interval [0, 3π] satisfying the equation 2sin2x + 5sinx − 3 = 0 is ","choices":["4","6","1","2"],"answer":"1","level":1})
db.question.insert({"question":"A body falling from rest under gravity passes a certain point P. It was at a distance of 400 m from P, 4s prior to passing through P. If g = 10 m/s2, then the height above the point P from where the body began to fall is ","choices":["720 m","900 m","320 m","680 m"],"answer":"1","level":2})